Most of you watching this
are probably in some kind of mental block
where you're
going to start in the new year and
that this year is going to be the best
year
ever. I don't care.
Here's some frameworks,
here's some actionable points, here's
some concepts. If you implement them,
you can do better without having to do
that
much more. Now, the first point I
was going to talk about
is shrinking your email
list. But before we even get into that,
you might realize I'm a bit nasally.
I've been very ill for the last week.
Snorted zero cocaine, drank zero booze,
but somehow got
struck down with the man flu. And what
was great about that
is the idea of filming
content was right up there in things I
wanted to do, next to wanking off a
stranger.
I didn't feel like being on camera.
I felt rough.
So all I did was pump out emails.
And even since Monday, what day is it?
Shut up. It's Tuesday, fuck. See,
I don't even know what fucking day it is.
Done $21,720.
I'll take a screenshot of that,
because you won't
believe me. I've done 14 grand yesterday.
How?
Don't know. And today, eight
and a half grand. See what I mean?
I basically wrote out a list of
passive-aggressive emails saying to
people, "Buy my
shit." Because on the 4th of Jan,
I'm putting prices up, which I am.
So the amazing thing here
is some days you're not going to have the
energy.
You're going to be ill.
You could be traveling.
You might even be on a plane.
And having an email database means
that I can still communicate with people,
whack,
whack, with an offer,
without having to worry about other stuff.
You're not a performative pony
that just comes on social media to make
videos all
the time to get people to buy your stuff.
Well, you are some of the time.
You need an avenue to communicate with
people.
Which brings me onto the main point of
that.
Some of you build your email lists like
it's a shrine, like it's something
that you
need to pray to, something impressive.
But if you don't utilize it,
it's like being a priest with a massive
cock.
It's a waste of utilities.
So what I want you to think about this is,
your email
list might have hit 5K,
might have even hit 10K.
Liv,
who we spoke about in the mentorship the
other day, her biggest concern is her
social media is popping off so much,
and we've built infrastructures
and things in
place so much, that her email list
is growing too aggressively.
She's now worried
that the amount she's paying just to her
email provider has over
doubled, and it's about to triple.
So I said, "Liv, let's shrink that bitch.
I want you firing offers, pop, pop, pop,
pop, pop, so much that
people actively are leaving." In sales,
they call this buy or die.
I think even I call it buy or die.
Literally hit people as much as you
can, because if your list is at 15,000,
let's leave everything off the table that
you think you know about business
or sales or marketing, whatever.
If I said to you,
"I want you to send so many fucking emails
that that list is at
7,500," yes, 7,500 people have left, but
there could be a flipping good amount of
new business that's just come in.
Build your email list,
then shrink it by proactively getting in
people's faces.
How often? Well,
I sent emails the day before Christmas
Eve.
Christmas Eve, for sure.
I emailed everyone on Christmas Day. Why?
Because I'm a psychopath.
But the other reason is,
not many people are going to
email you on Christmas Day.
So you're bored,
you've had a couple glasses of
champagne, you've sat on the sofa,
one of your clients has just left you.
I'm going to turn up there and go,
"Buy my shit." And it works.
Shrinking your list is a great thing,
because if you do dwindle it down
and it ends
up being like a six-inch pecker like that,
then you're going to go, "Holy Jesus,
I best grow my email list," which
is a good feeling to have.
Some people out there have big email lists
that they don't hit because they're
scared of shrinking it,
and the fear of not shrinking it means
that you suck at
business. Okay, point number two.
I have been ill this week,
as you may have known,
because I won't stop complaining
about it.
So the second thing I started doing
is reposting old reels.
Not just from last year,
but the year before. Why?
Because my posting frequency on Instagram
was zero.
I, like many of you,
are running into a cycle of promotions to
launch a January
challenge. I need to be active.
I need to be in people's faces.
And here's the thing.
If you're making one new piece of content
a day and you
repurpose an old video,
you've doubled your posting frequency for
a start.
So already you've gone from wherever you
are to more, to double.
If you were to add two old posts,
you'd triple it.
Some comments are going to go,
"I've already seen this one." I go, "Yeah,
but the
majority of people fucking didn't." And
if you go back to that last post, the last
time you posted it,
let's look at the views to your follower
ratio, or the amount
of likes to your follower ratio. Even
if 50% haven't seen it,
that's fine to repost. And
if someone's going to be out there and go,
"Ugh, I've already seen that post,
I'm unfollowing you,"
they were not going to slip off the edge
of their seat and buy your shit.
So you can fuck off.
That's the reality of it.
The people that you want
that do business with you,
that buy your stuff, that
become Nutonic drinkers,
are the type of people that go, "Mate,
loved it the first time you posted it.
Have a fucking double tap from me." They
know what you're doing.
They go, "James is a good cunt.
He's obviously got such an impact on
people through the first time he's posted
it, he's bloody posted it again. Love it.
Great. Cheers,
mate." So for those of you coming out into
2026, you
have a content frequency postage of one
post a day.
Double it with the last year's post.
Now, if you didn't post last year,
that's the price you pay.
And maybe just push that into 2027.
For those of you guys out there
that had some videos absolutely pop the
fuck
off this year, sometimes you go, "Oh,
have you reposted it?
How did it do?" "No, I haven't." Oh,
so you won the lottery
and you didn't decide
to buy another ticket. Cool. If not,
have you remade it but better? No.
If you haven't done that,
you're an idiot because you pretty much...
Let's think about "Landman" because we're
watching it at the moment, and who's
fitter, the daughter or the wife?
No one knows. No one knows.
You're out there,
you're putting pump jacks in the ground
and you struck oil, and
you've decided to go to another part of
Midland to strike oil.
Mate, put another pump jack in that place.
You've struck oil. You've struck gold.
Double up. You know it's going to work,
so do it again, brother.
So repurposing is the lowest barrier to
entry because it doesn't take long, and
sometimes I'm not even going to beat
around the bush.
The Coke Zero female fat loss
and another video I've done went
super mega fucking viral second
or third time I repurposed it.
And if someone's got a problem with that,
like I said, they're not going to buy
shit. Moving on. Of course,
Nutonic's good.
When writing your email marketing
campaigns in the new year,
if you're unsure,
because a lot of the time you sit here in
front of your laptop, you've got nothing
to write about, go to your Facebook mems,
screenshot something that happened.
Go to your camera roll on this day last
year.
There are some visual
and storytelling hooks
that we can utilize, and I don't think
I've spoken about this enough.
So for instance, today
is the 30th of December.
If you're watching this video
and it's coming out on the 31st,
Declan fucked up.
Because Oi,
I know you haven't done any editing for a
week, brother, because I've
been ill. You've been living good
if this ain't out tonight.
Storytelling hook.
I could go to the 30th of December last
year. I might even do that right now.
I might even do that right now. What
was I doing 30th of December last year?
Isn't it mad when you scroll through your
camera roll these days and you're
thinking, "Christ alive,
the amount of life that's passed us by."
Okay,
30th of December. Okay, we're in November.
30th of December.
Oh, Jesus Christ, James,
you've got a lot of sh-
Fucking shit going on here.
18th of December, keep going.
27th of December,
28th. Okay, 30th of December, my son
was still wearing
a little helmet because he had a flat
head. Oh, what a little man.
He wasn't even walking last year. Anyway,
I'm not going to lie,
it wasn't the most thrilling of days,
but I could've just
taken a picture from the 31st,
and who's going to check me?
Send the fucking cops.
Call the cops. There's a story.
On this day last year, I did this.
We've just got a segment into a story.
Or eight years ago today,
or nine years ago yesterday,
I moved to bloody Australia.
And I thought to myself, what
was good about that journey
was the fact that I've
still got the receipt from the time I had
to stop off in Beijing Airport for 10
hours. So I was like, first of all,
relatability. Hey, I used to be poor.
Not anymore, and neither will you.
And I had to fly Air China,
watch "Saving Private Ryan" three times in
Mandarin.
Had to sit on the floor because my laptop
needed to be plugged in.
And the only film I had on me,
because in China,
you can't access anything without
a VPN. Didn't have a VPN.
I couldn't get Gmail, YouTube, whatever.
In the end,
watched "Dallas Buyers Club,"
and I spent the other eight hours and
four minutes on the stop-off thinking
that I had AIDS.
And the thing about AIDS
is there's not much research on it
when you haven't
got Google. So cheers to the CCP for that.
So when it comes to email marketing in
2026,
if you haven't got anything to write,
just go to your memes,
go to your Facebook memes. Hell,
go to your camera roll.
Go back in. There
are thousands of stories in there.
The more crazy, the better. Moving on.
One thing that I've seen this year is
that people will do amazing content,
repost stuff, double down on outliers,
do good call to actions, use
ManyChat,
get people onto their email list,
use amazing lead magnets.
They will do all of these things, right?
Amazing email marketing emails.
Someone gets to the sales page,
look at your title.
You should have, when I land on your page,
don't give a shit about your brand.
I want a title, subtitle, VSL. That's it.
And just don't be so generic. So
if you're a personal trainer,
don't be like,
"Get in the best shape of your life.
Helping people discover the journey of
self-confidence."
So that, if you're an accountant,
"Pay less tax." If you're a physio,
"Say goodbye to back pain." It's shit.
It's shit.
It's shit. If I was a physio, I would say,
"You're injury-prone because you're
weak as piss." Subheading,
"With my strength program,
I'm not going to give you
rehab.
I'm going to make you a fucking weapon
using strength conditioning.
So the next time an injury comes to get
you, your strength
and competence will make
that injury fuck off." If I
was an accountant, I'd be like,
"Stop giving money to
the government that you didn't need to."
Great title. I'm making these up.
There's a teleprompter there. This
is in the brain, brother.
Subtitle,
"We specialize in helping businesses pay
less tax, which
means more money for you to spend on the
things you love, like your family, your
friends,
or getting a new car." Because I'll read
that and I'll go, "I want that.
I want that.
So give me that." Look at your stuff.
If it's generic or if
I even catch a whiff of ChatGPT, I'm gone.
And do you know what?
We're going to make this a point within
the point.
Some of you out there
are being so misled by gurus online saying
that you need to use AI. Guess what?
AI is retarded at sales copy. AI
is retarded at
ideation. And what they're doing
is by telling you to put your sales page
into
flipping AI, they
are putting you back 10 years.
You need to sit there, and this
is the thing.
If I locked you in a room with a notepad
and a bit of pen and paper, you would do
much better at ideation,
coming up with good ideas and hooks,
than you would
anywhere else. For so many of you,
if I said,
"Lock yourself in a dark room and
come up with 40 YouTube titles," you'll
come up with 10 that are better than what
AI can do.
You're being sold the dream with AI.
It's good,
but it's a 20K a year personal assistant
who's retarded,
but you're fine with them being retarded
because they're your assistant. Stop.
Give me a good idea. AI is not there yet.
And if you want to get ahead,
you need to be able to think up
and ideate things
that are better than AI,
which at this stage is pretty easy.
The people selling you the AI dream just
want you to buy some AI product that
they're doing, so you become, "Oh, AI, AI,
AI, AI, AI." It's pathetic.
Moving on. Some of you,
when you're going to be putting out your
short-form content
online, get the captions,
just put them down here.
Not across the face,
not across the money maker,
but here's fine because people's
eyes will go from here to here.
I'll tell you what, Declan,
if you don't mind in
the edit, as I'm talking now,
just give me some cool,
chilled captions down there.
Now put them across my face
and make it show them how flipping
annoying it is, and
now put the captions at the very bottom,
which means their eyes have to travel a
long way between top and bottom.
You get the fucking point.
So when that's in portrait,
it looks much worse.
And also, I've seen captions that
are way too much.
In the Discord most days, I'm like, "Kit,
fucking calm them captions down,
brother." But I've never said ever to
anyone, "Oh, your captions
are a bit boring."
Never have. So instead, please,
chilled captions.
Nothing fucking crazy.
Just below the chin is fine.
I want my eyes to go from captions to
eyes, captions to eyes.
Don't overcook it, brother. Okay,
next point I want to talk about
is some of you do
too much in your business. You do.
And it could be way too many one-to-one
calls,
which I've dropped.
I don't do them anymore.
Or it could be things like check-ins with
clients, whether physio, PT, whatever it
is.
And I've said to you to get rid of those.
Because for a lot of you,
your business operates way better
if you're not wasting
dozens of hours a week having to talk to
people. So don't just say, "Hey, guys.
Moving forward,
I'm dropping one-to-one check-ins." Create
a new system, a
new program that even sounds better.
So for instance, case in point, I
was a face-to-face PT for years.
I didn't just say, "Hey, guys.
I'm moving online." I said, "Guys.
I'm creating the James Smith Online
Personal Training Inner Circle." I
was like, I
need to make what I had before look worse.
Before, you saw me for one hour a week.
With this, I'm with you seven days a week.
Constant around-the-clock support.
Contact whenever you need it.
And instead of paying me to give you one
session,
you're paying me to write a program
that entails every single session.
The majority of you doing three sessions
plus a week.
So you're not just tripling your value.
You're getting daily touchpoints and...
Gee, I'm even saying it out loud.
I'm making this up
and it's making me want to buy
it.
So when you drop your one-to-one calls,
you go, "Guys.
We've created a new system to deliver the
best results with you.
And it's so good,
we don't even need to do the one-to-one
check-ins anymore." And
you don't say,
"I'm doing it to clear up time so I don't
have to do so
many hours of... You know, look,
your life's important. You've got kids.
You've got aspirations.
You've got things you need to do.
Stop wasting it on the phone with me.
Instead, we're going to replace
that with an added session of whatever it
is a week." Because most of you
are doing too much operating your
business, and a
lot of people don't even want that.
Case in point, people in my Discord.
When they want their landing page
reviewed,
why jump on a call with me for over a
grand an hour when you can just put it in
the Discord?
Because I can review it in fucking 38
seconds.
And I'll be honest with you,
there's something I do in the Discord with
all of my
clients, and they'll know it.
They might not know it till they've seen
this video.
I give them three things.
Three things max.
So I go onto your landing page.
I go, "This font is shit.
I want it dark mode because I do not like
white
background, black text.
And your VSL needs to come up
and your brand needs to go."
They go, "Anything else?" I go,
"Do the fucking changes,
then come back." Then they
come back.
I'll give them another three things.
I don't want to overwhelm people,
but I don't want to overwhelm myself
either.
Then I can give someone three things to
do. It's taken me 38 seconds to review it.
It's going to be 42 seconds to give them
the fucking feedback back.
That's how we keep things where I can do a
lot, give a lot.
They don't have to spend thousands of
fucking dollars on one-to-one calls.
I create this so they get the best result
for the least amount of financial burden.
But also,
it means I haven't got to spend fucking
hours on calls, because a lot of
the time, over 60 minutes,
you get fucking five things done.
I can do it in 38 seconds.
So don't discount
when you're getting rid of these
things. Reframe it.
Change it into something new.
Create a new product.
That's how this works.
The next point isn't...
I'm just going to say this anyway.
By the way, on the 4th of January,
I'm putting my rates up.
They're going up by $1,000. Reason being,
it's too cheap. Simple as.
Second reason,
I need to do less because I'm about to
rebuild Business
Mentorship 3.0. From 1.0 to 2.0,
I'd spent a year working with
people.
I showed people in the Discord the other
day, I had 49,000 messages in the
Discord last year. I've learnt a lot,
so I made Mentorship 2.0.
I need to take a month off pretty much
from doing this so I can rebuild
3.0 with everything I've learnt from the
last two years.
And then it will go up another thousand.
So if you want to save yourself two grand,
you've got five days.
Anyway, next thing I want to talk about
is making buying the priority.
For so many of you in your sales system,
people are going to be umming and ahing
and whatever. Just say to people, "Look,
just buy." Just buy.
If you have a problem, I'll refund you.
Right now, for my James Smith Academy,
I'm doing a six-month challenge.
For that, I've said to people,
there's a one-month money-back guarantee.
They go, "Oh, I'm not sure about...
I'm not..." "Look, there's a guarantee.
Just buy, join. Any issues,
I'll refund you." Because I know once
people are in,
they see how good the app is,
and they get a feel for the platform,
they're going
to stay in.
And let's say the success rate of that
is 90%, I'd rather deal with
the 10% of refunds than I would having to
fuck around in this part of the
funnel. So if your funnel is like that,
just push them past the sales point.
If some come back over the top, fine,
refund.
Everything, "Oh,
I really want to just get on a call." Tell
you what, you join.
You buy six months or three months
or two months or four months
or whatever it is.
I'll jump on a call with you tomorrow.
But it's not a sales call.
It'll be an onboarding call.
Because then the people
that aren't going to buy or
the people that are going to waste your
time aren't going to go that extra mile to
actually join.
And here's the most important thing.
And it's about identifying
when within your business you're not doing
something.
So for instance,
I haven't posted a video on this channel,
wee,
since two weeks.
And once you've had a bit of time away
from a channel, it becomes easy to forget
about it. It becomes easy to go, "Oh,
do I really need to put...
Oh, maybe I'll just do it tomorrow.
Oh,
I'm having a bit of..." You've just got to
get back into it.
I don't care if you haven't posted short
form in a while.
Get back into it today, tomorrow.
You haven't written emails in a while.
Send one today.
You haven't put together a new offer in a
while. Create one today.
This video today, I'll be honest, I live,
I don't know, about a kilometer away.
I get in the car. For me,
I didn't want to come here.
I'll be honest, I'm still a bit ill,
but I needed to get back in.
I needed to get the reps back in.
So I got in the car, I opened ChatGPT,
and I
dictated to it for the two-minute drive it
takes to get here, and I just came up
with 11 points off the top of my head
because coming up and turning
up and making a video
is more important than anything
that I've said.
For me, and this is the same for you,
the only thing I cannot stand is
inaction.
You cannot cry about the results
that you didn't get from the thing you
didn't do. It's imperative
that whatever part of your business you
are lacking or
not turning up to, fucking turn up.
Even if this video gets 1,000 views,
I don't give a shit because I can look at
that
failed video and go, "I fucking turned up.
I came, I gave it some effort,
and probably get some fucking sales out of
it."
There's some links in the description.
You can use the comments to ask me stuff.
Like I said,
I'm not even going to promote
that hard that prices are going up
because if you join in a month's time,
I get more of your money to deliver the
same
amount of work. So, bersh. Anyway,
you've got some more learning to do.
If you're not going to buy my stuff,
then at least watch this video here
because
the more of my content you watch,
the more likely you are to buy my shit.
So it's like a full circle.
Great for the average view duration as
well. All right.
Bye-bye.